# Azmeer Raja M

### MOBILE APPLICATION DEVELOPER

### CONTACT

+919159154786



azmeerraaja@live.com



Bengaluru



### **EDUCATION**

2010 - 2014

B.Tech – IT (CGPA-7.1)

Hindusthan Institute Of Technology, Coimbatore

2008 - 2010

Higher Secondary (85%)

Veveaham Higher Secondary School, Dharapuram

2007 - 2008

S.S.L.C (69%)

Veveaham Higher Secondary School,Dharapuram

#### SKILLS SUMMARY

Framework: Android, Ionic

Platforms: IOS & ANDROID

Languages: JAVA, ANGULAR JS,C#,PHP

Addons: JSON, XML, FIREBASE,

**GIT, AWS REST** 

Database: MySQL, SQLite, ORACLE

**Tools: Android Studio IDE, Ms Visual Studio 15,** 

IIS ,Oracle SQL

**Design: Adobe Photoshop** 

### PERSONAL PROFILE

Father's Name: Mohamed Rabi A(Late)

Mother's Name: Vahida Banu M

Date of Birth : 31/12/1992

**Mother Tongue : Tamil** 

### Languages known

Speak Read Write

English ✓ ✓

Tamil ✓ ✓ ✓

Hindi - ✓ -

### Prefered Location:

<mark>Bangalore/Bengaluru</mark>

### Availability:

Immediate Joining

### Profile

Self-directed and Motivated Android Application Developer with 7+ **years of** experience building, integrating, testing, deploying and supporting Android applications for mobile and tablet devices on the Android platform seeks a position with a top technology firm.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

March 2020 - Present

SENIOR ANDROID DEVELOPER CodeCatalysts Private Ltd

December 2018 -February 2020

ANDROID APPLICATION DEVELOPER

Doers Tech Enterprise Solutions Private Ltd

**April 2015 – November 2018** 

SENIOR ASSOCIATE – ANDROID APPLICATION DEVELOPER *The Chennai Silks – Corporate Office.* 

### PROFESSIONAL SKILL SET

- Proven knowledge of Android SDK, different versions of Android, and how to deal with different screen sizes
- Familiarity with **RESTful APIs** to connect Android applications to back-end services in both **php codeignitor and c# MVC**
- Proven knowledge of Android UI design principles, patterns, and best practices
- Experience with offline storage, threading, and performance tuning
- Proven Knowledge in IONIC Framework (Cordova) with vast
   Working Experience in Plugins like Map , Payment Gateway and
   Bluetooth Peripherals
- Knowledge of the open-source Android ecosystem and the libraries available for common tasks
- Ability to understand business requirements and translate them into technical requirements
- Familiarity with cloud message APIs and push notifications
- A knack for benchmarking and optimization
- Understanding of Google's Android design principles and interface guidelines
- Proficient understanding of code versioning tools, such as **Git**,Teams Foundation svn .
- Hands On Experience in Design, Develop, Deploy in Both
   Google and Apple Play Stores
- Strong Knowledge in Payment Gate Way Integrations both Native android and ionic
- Knowledge of profile management and uploading build to both the play stores

## **Projects**

### **CODECATALYSTS**

### HOPCOMS ONLINE -HOPCOMS Online is an E-Commerce App

Initiated For the Sole Benefit of Our Farmers , The Vegetables and Fruits Are directly Procured from The Farmers and Sold To the Customers , This is a Karnataka State Government Aided Project Through the HOPCOMS Firm.

### **IONIC Framework:**

Android URL: <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=f2c.hopcoms.online">https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=f2c.hopcoms.online</a> IOS URL: <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/hopcoms-online/id1581744250">https://apps.apple.com/us/app/hopcoms-online/id1581744250</a>

### Roles and Responsibilities:

- Analyzing and developing Application requirements.
- Optimized to support all devices and to reduce bugs immediately.
- Main Role: Requirement Gathering, Design, Development And Launch
- Team Strength: 4

NOTE: This Ecommerce App Has two Support Apps namely HOPCOMS SHOP and HOPCOMS DELIVERY which are not in Play store. Which Provides All the In House Functionalities like Add Products, Edit Products, Assign Order to Delivery Executive, Approve or cancel orders, Full Order Lifecycle .And Delivery app Has Functionalities of Assigned orders and Delivery Status with Google Routes Api

KKISSAN – KKISAN App is a Admin App for the Farmer Details Which are maintained by Karnataka Government (Agriculture Department of Karnataka) to keep track of the Farmer Personal Details and the Subsidies they Claimed for the Machinery , Infectionary, and Other Land Related Details , Which is used by RSK, JDA, ADA, HOA Officers.

### Native Android:

Android URL: <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.agrilinspection">https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.agrilinspection</a>

### Roles and Responsibilities:

- Analyzing and developing Application requirements.
- Optimized to support all devices and to reduce bugs immediately.
- Main Role: Requirement Gathering, Design, Development And Launch
- Team Strength: 4

# KKISSAN SMARTCARD - KKISAN Smartcard App is also Admin

App for the Farmer Details Which are maintained by Karnataka Government (Agriculture Department of Karnataka) to keep track of the Farmer Personal Details Solely, Which is used by RSK only

### Native Android:

Android URL: <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.codecatalysts.kkisan.smart.card">https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.codecatalysts.kkisan.smart.card</a>

### Roles and Responsibilities:

- Analyzing and developing Application requirements.
- Optimized to support all devices and to reduce bugs immediately.
- Main Role: Requirement Gathering, Design, Development And Launch
- Team Strength: 4

NOQ Store – NOQ self-checkout store provides friction-less shopping experience and enables Customers to scan, pay, and bag their purchases without Any Human assistance. noQ creates a Frictionless shopping experience by skipping traditional checkout concepts with long queue.

#### **IONIC Framework:**

Android URL: <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.doerstech.noqapp&hl=en">https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.doerstech.noqapp&hl=en</a> IOS URL: <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/noq-store/id1464901265">https://apps.apple.com/us/app/noq-store/id1464901265</a>

### Roles and Responsibilities:

- Analyzing and developing Application requirements.
- Optimized to support all devices and to reduce bugs immediately.
- Main Role: Whole Process Has Been done By Self (Requirement Gathering, Design, Webservice, Development And Launch)
- Team Strength: 2

### NOQ Store KIOSK - NOQ self-checkout store provides friction-less

shopping experience and enables Customers to scan, pay, and bag their purchases without Any Human assistance. noQ creates a Frictionless shopping experience by skipping traditional checkout concepts with long queue.

### Native Android:

#### Android URL:

 $\frac{https://play.google.com/apps/publish/?account=6589455512920297034\#AppDashboardPlace:p=noq.doers.kiosk\&appid=4972832525101403912$ 

### Roles and Responsibilities:

- Analyzing and developing Application requirements.
- Optimized to support all devices and to reduce bugs immediately.
- Main Role: Whole Process Has Been done By Self (Requirement Gathering, Design, Webservice, Development And Launch)
- Team Stregnth: 1

### NOQ Store Admin - Admin App For NOQ Store Reporting Purpose

### An In-house App.

### Roles and Responsibilities:

- Analyzing and developing Application requirements.
- Optimized to support all devices and to reduce bugs immediately.
- Main Role: Whole Process Has Been done By Self (Requirement Gathering, Design, Webservice, Development And Launch)
- Team Strength: 2

### OVOLATTE - Bakery Application

Framework - Code Igniter and Ionic

Team size - 03

Role - Design and Developer

Platform - Android and IOS

Skills Used - Java, XML, PHP, HTML and JavaScript

Database - SQLite and MySQL

Google Play URL - <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.doers.ovolatte">https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.doers.ovolatte</a>

(This app is only designed for Android Tablets)

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.doers.ovolatteadmin

### **Description:**

Point Of Sale application is created for Bakery and Cake shop. Creatively designed with emerging technology to work with Android tablets and mobile phones and POS device where Employee Attendance with location tracking, order booking, order delivery, order cancellation and take away sales can be performed in few clicks with bill printing. And Inventory management through material Request, Material Receipt, Stock Transfer with stock moving Report.

### The Chennai Silks

Several In House Apps And TWO Apps In Playstore (TCS PURCHASE and TJ CHIT )

NOTE: The Functionalities and the features in These Apps are Confidential as per the Firm Rules and Regulations.

### Roles and Responsibilities:

- Analyzing and developing Application requirements.
- Optimized to support all devices and to reduce bugs immediately.
- Only Authorized persons can be able to login.
- Team Size: 1
- Main Role: All of The Apps are Handled By Self (Requirement Gathering, Design, Web service, Development And Launch)

I do hereby declare that the information given above are true and correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Place: Bengaluru Azmeer Raja M

Date: